They hung down.
Do you remember this song?  Hello, Andrey.
So what should we talk about today?
[laughter]
I won't be with you.
Why?
Well, I don't want to.
You won't tell me why there is
gasoline in Kharkov.
I don’t live in Kharkov, honestly I don’t know
why there is gasoline there.
There you see.
So, is it possible?  Can I tell you
how much gas we have?
How many?
Let me tell you how much
gasoline costs here.
Let's.
6240.
Super.
And where is this?
In Samara.
What, you still don’t know where I live
?
Samara.  I have a
bunch of weirdos here every day.
Got it, got it.
Listen, how is it that
Ukraine is able to attack
Russian territory without any obstacles?
How is this unhindered?
Well, somehow her drones fly by calmly and
unhindered.
Ah, well, listen, how are
ballistics going in Ukraine?
Ukraine's ballistics have nothing to
shoot down ballistics with.  It makes sense.
Ah, well, and these are like these videos,
there is Gerani hammering on these locomotives
.
No, it's not Gerani that's hitting the locomotives, it's the ones that are
close to the border, yes, on
FPV, on control, yes.
Well, look, these are frontline zones,
yes, frontline zones.  But how is it that
Ukraine is able to penetrate into
Russia from 2,000 km to 1,000 km?
Well, I think that this is
precisely with Western intelligence,
radio-technical, specifically satellite.
Precisely satellite.
Well, it's a complex topic, actually.  It's actually
complicated, and they wouldn't have been able
to cope with the Ukrainians on their own.  Of
course not.  Well, well, let's do it this way.  It is not
Ukraine that is fighting at all, but the West that is fighting for no reason.   Yes.
Why can't Russia
counter this attack?
Well, listen, when the entire
civilized world is fighting against you, no matter how hard it is.   Yes.
Well, yes, it is difficult.   So
, it turns out that when Russia itself fought,
like in the Russo-Japanese War, it got its comeuppance, right?  But
when it fought alongside the
civilized world, it was able to
win in coalition with the world, but when it fought against the
coalition, it lost the Crimean War to the
world coalition.  True,
when
Russia lost the Crimean War.
Crimean, yes.
And then Crimea remained Russia.
M because there were some other
agreements later.  And the Crimean War...
Well, look.  Russia lost the Crimean War
.
Okay,
yes.  Fine.
And Russian-Japanese too.
Yes, we lost the Russo-Japanese war.
Japanese and also the First World War.
Look, Russian, yes.  And
they lost the First World War.  The Russians lost to the Japanese in a completely
dry manner.  Yes.  Tsushima.  In short,
come on, come on, let's bend our fingers.
Russian-Japanese, Crimean.
Eh, what other one?
Russian-Chechen first.
Oh, come on.  Yeah, well, let's not
get into that, please.
Why not climb?  They lost, they lost, they
shamefully withdrew their troops, and signed the Treaty
of Khasavyur.
If we go there now, we'll have a second
episode, you know?
Well, we lost, we lost.
No, no, nobody lost anything.
How did you not lose?  They took it out.  Yes.  It was me
then, inexperienced and young, so to speak, who
fell for these sort of
tricks of yours, that there was some what’s his name, I don’t
remember, no, my God,
Kosavurnovskiy, yes, there were agreements,
yes, an
agreement,
and what was there?
No, we lost, look.  We lost, we
withdrew our troops, we lost, yes,
we lost the Afghan war, yes?
Why?  For what?
Look, I took, like, in the Crimean
War, yes,
in the Crimean War, yes, you lost, look,
you lost to the coalition of the Ottoman Empire,
Great Britain, France and the Serbian
Kingdom.  Okay,
great.  Great.
Here [clears throat] Parisian.
Come on, come on, come on, count on your fingers
how much you lost.  Let's count on our
fingers how many we lost.
Eh, we also lost the Russian-Polish war
.  Yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes.
They signed the Brest Peace Treaty and that was it.  Well,
we lost the first Chechen war.
What?
Understood.  Ah, the Soviet-Polish war, right?   Yes.
2020s.
And which ones?  Look, can you tell me now
what war Russia won
without being in a coalition with other Western
powers?  Yes.  Which war was won?  Yes.
without the support of Western powers.  Name
the Mongols,
when did you fight, when
was the Russo-Mongol War?
Through, well, this is the 15th century.
XV century, Russian-Mongolian war.
When were the Mongols expelled from
Russian territory?
In short, the Mongols were not expelled.  And the Mongols,
like, when Genghis Khan died, the Golden Horde
split into western and eastern.  That's all
, in short.  And the Mongols were not there.
You had Tatars there.
And so it's good.  When were the Tatars expelled?
Never kicked out.  They remained with you
, like, well, you are the successor of the Golden
Horde.  Can you tell me, look, when
you, here, Russia, yes, take it for
No, wait, wait.  We we paid the
yoke.  The yoke was like this.  Fine.  Okay,
let's do it.  Come on, tell me, over the last
500 years, over the last 500 years
you swore, this is the first time I've ever sworn at you.
And look, tell me, over the last 500
years, what wars has Russia won
on its own?  Not in coalitions?
Not in the coalition.  Fine.  Uh, Swedish?
No, there was a coalition against Sweden,
yes, with Russia, yes.  They were Western
because Sweden was an empire, yes, it had them with
it.  Come on, watch now.  So, it is
now,
because there were Europeans against Charles
.  So, so.  Look, the
Great Northern War, 1700 and 1721
.
On the one hand, the conflict was fought against the
Swedish Empire, and on the other hand, against
Peter the Great's Muscovite Kingdom, yes, Denmark and
Norway, the Saxon Electorate, the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth,
right?  So, it
was a huge global coalition at that
time, right?
Well, they didn't fight with them together
.
Aggregate Look again, look again,
again.  No, look, the Northern War, yes,
it's called No, it's stop.  No, no, that's what it was
called.
Northern anti-Swedish coalition.
Yes, that's right, yes,
yes.
Okay, I agree.
So, North, that is, as a
result of this victory, each country
there has its own.  The Northern Anti-Swedish
Coalition, also known as the Northern
Union, is a military-political bloc
created in 1699.  His goal was to
defeat the Swedish Empire and redistribute
its possessions in the Baltic and Northern Europe.
The coalition became
the initiator and so on, right?  That is, it
turns out that these states
had such talented people at that time that they
could come to an agreement with such a huge
issue.  Yes, well, because, yes,
you were also against Napoleon in, name it to me,
yes, still, let's return to the question of
which war was won, which wars
were won without a coalition.  So far you can't name anything
without a coalition.  Well, maybe such wars
simply don’t happen.
Well, why?  For example,
you fought the Crimean War without a coalition and lost.   The
Russo-Japanese War was lost without a coalition.
Unfortunately, I'm not very familiar with the Crimean one
.  Well, there was probably a coalition there too
.
No, the coalition was against Russia. It was not against
Russia.
What kind of Cossacks are they?  The Cossacks were already part of the
Russian Empire.
Exactly,
of course.  We've already met with Pereyaslavskaya Rada.  It's
already past, in short, damn, almost two centuries have
passed.
Galician,
what?
Golitsy Cossacks.
Galicia.  No, Galicia was part of
Austria-Hungary.  This is how it is,
you see.
Well then, let's see which one.  Here's a simple
question.  Russia says, we have everything going on there,
all the wars in Europe that
Russia won, it won in each case as part of
European coalitions.  He began
to tell Russia that this is it, now let's do it.
Where did he say that?
What?
Well, you just said there that you
did it to Russia with your own hands, that’s all.
I am saying that Russia won all the wars it
won in Europe as
part of some European coalitions with
Western powers.  Without Western powers,
Russia has won nothing, as
its war in Ukraine now demonstrates.
Stop, stop.  Russia wars.  Come on,
Russia grew from what period, from what period?
Take it over the last 500 years.
Well, there wasn't any back then.  At that time there were still
feudal fragmentations.
Well then, take it.  over the last 500 years, well,
from today's 500 years, both the Soviet
Union and the Russian Empire, yes, what did it
win, in short, yes, what wars did
it win over the last 500 years on its own
without those damned Anglo-Saxons.
Now I'll try to see
what else it is.
Where can I watch this?  I don't even
know where to watch it.
Okay, let me get ready tomorrow.
No, then let's do it now.
I don’t know, right now I just... Just take a look
at artificial
intelligence.
Well, remember.  Well, look, you are the
great Russian nation.  Well, what did you
win?  What are yours, like this?  Come on
Swede, Swedish war.  This is Peter [laughter] I.
This is the northern northern.  Well, we
shot in the coalition.  All.
OK.  What kind of coalition was there?   Well,
this is the northern one.  I read it to you.
I read it to you.  Denmark, Norway, Polish-
Lithuanian Commonwealth.  This is the Battle of Poltava.
Where is it?
Once again, look again, once again I’m
telling you, yes, that Northern War, that
twenty-first year, yes, you waged it as
part of a coalition, right?
Fine.  Where was the Danish fleet?
They also fought with the Swedes in the Baltic and so
on.  Yes, absolutely.
This is a fact.  Well, it's like,
no-no, no, come on.
Good,
good.  There, well, Russian was decisive, everything
was decisive.  Everything was decisive.
Yes, yes, yes.  Everything is decisive.
This is also good.  Oh, stop, stop, stop,
look, stop.  Yes, stop.
Yes, Hanover, Prussia
and Great Britain also joined this coalition, yes, they had
their own territorial
claims against Sweden and Germany.  So
no need, no need.
Fine.  Look, yes, as a result of the
civil peace treaty, yes, then as
a result of the Northern War, Russia
gained access to the Baltic Sea, Denmark
strengthened its position in Northern
Germany, and so on and so forth.   Yes.
What you won, name me
one war that you won without a
coalition.
Without a coalition.  Just one?  Give me
at least one right now, right now.   Yes.
E- 2008.
Oh, right, when you attacked Georgia.
Agree.  Yes, yes, you played.  They attacked.
Why did you attack?  Why did you attack?
[clears throat]
Well, war, yes.  I understand.  A
worthy opponent.
Again.  Once again I understood.  Look, we won’t
give a worthy example now, yes
.  In 2008, you won the war with
Georgia.  You tell me what I have as a
memory, what if I figure it out, if You didn’t
give me time
to figure it out.  No, stop and figure it out.  I
will prepare.
Well, tomorrow I'll get ready and figure it out.
Understood.  Okay, right now, right now, just a
second.
Wait, what about 812, what kind of coalition
was there?
What about
812?
So, it would be anti, listen, the
anti-Napoleonic coalition - that
was all of Europe and Britain, and, in short, who was
n’t there.   It's
definitely there,
right?  Look.  And Sweden was
against Napoleon back then, already in 812, I think.
Got it, got it.
There, there, against Napoleon.  What is the name of
Bestro, what is it called in this, what is it called,
that
cafe in Paris.
Again.  Look again at the Battle of
Waterloo, in short, all of
Europe was against Napoleon.  This is definite.   Just like
against Hitler, yes.
Well, Hitler was also in the coalition.
So, look, come on.  Interesting, I
asked Jemina a question, didn't I?  What, look,
what wars over the last 500 years has Russia
won without the help of other countries and
coalitions?  So.
So
, no, there are no independent victories,
because where Russia won,
it was as part of some coalition with
other European states.
So, is
this good or bad?   That's
not what I'm saying, look, when you,
yes, were in alliance with the lousy European Union,
yes, with these Anglo-Saxons, you could
win and so on.  As soon as you
find yourself, well, let's say, with an
international coalition against you, you
somehow
miss the attacks on your territories.   Is it
true?
Possibly, possibly.  What, what's wrong with that?
Well, I just wanted to see something about greatness
, right?  That is, it turns out that
this imaginary greatness, yes, and the
opposition to the West, it turns out
that without the help of the West, Russia cannot do
anything,
greatness or not, if Russia stands
against a coalition of these Western countries.
Ah, I get it.  All.  That is, now you have
greatness, yes, that you stand up, that you
endure attacks on your territories.
Well, in the Crimean War, for example,
in the Crimean War you
made territorial concessions to these countries.
And who won?
For the coalition,
yes.  And according to the peace treaty you gave up
part of your territories.  Yes.
Fine.  Type in Jimin who won the
Crimean War.  Let's
dial.
Okay,
let's go.  Who won the Crimean War and
what was its territorial outcome?
So, in the Crimean War, she
gave it to me in Ukrainian.  Thus, in 1853-1856, a
coalition of states, including
Great
Britain, France, the Ottoman Empire and the
Kingdom of Sardinia, won the victory.  The Russian
Empire knew defeat, like it was time to
suffer a defeat.  So, [laughter]
uh, the Treaty of Paris, 1856,
yes, as a result of that war.  So,
Russia, uh, sort of waited for the
neutralization of the Black Sea.  So,
territorial concessions, right?  Russia
ceded to the Ottoman Empire part of
Bessarabia,
that is, the southern, southwestern part, which is on the
Danube.  Russia also lost the right to
protectorate over Moldova and so on.   Yes.
That's all.  Russia lost the Crimean
War and signed a defeatist
peace treaty.
Badly.
You see how weak our authorities were back then
.
No, it’s not that the authorities are weak.  The thing is,
when the Russians,
yes, hate Europe so much, I'm telling you
that we can repeat it.  It turns out that
without Europe they could never
win.  Never.   Yes.
Well, no, you see, several situations have changed here
.
Explain.  Europe is drowning.  Drowned in her
wealth, in her debauchery.  Yes,
you remember how the Roman
Empire fell again.   About the
same thing.  About the same
.
Well, that is, when she became too, too
rich, too corrupted.
Understood?
And fell apart.
Well, over time, yes, I
understood.  Well, in short, let's summarize the
result of our agreement.  We couldn't
find these wars, yes, which Russia
itself won here in Europe,
yes.  Somehow it turned out that when she had
some European allies with her
, she won.  And so,
I’m not prepared, I told you.  I'm not
prepared.  He said 2008, and yes
, little Georgia was attacked in 2008
and won.   There is
no market here.
Little little Georgia.  Little
Georgia plus the USA.
And little Georgia plus the USA fought.  Did you
fight with the USA in Georgia?   Yes.
What US troops were stationed on
Georgian territory?
Oh, listen, these are the same troops that
wanted Russian troops in Donbass.
Got it, got it.  Okay, now I understand.  Then you,
damn, you are really cool.  You
defeated the United States in Georgia in 2008.  You bombed the
American army there.  Understood?  Okay, I'll
run on.
You understand, Russia, in short, all of
Russia’s greatness has been deflated by the fact that they, on
their own, without the help of the West,
yes, were able to defeat Georgia in 2008.   Do
you understand?
Like, subscribe, comment.  Subscribe to
our WhatsApp channel.  Here is the QR code.  There,
news similar to that
in the Telegram channel is posted for those who don’t have
Telegram or who don’t use it.  and for
other reasons.